

□ 952-297-6289 | ☑ imsure95@gmail.com | **☆** imsure.github.io | **回** imsure | **i** shuo-yang-12ab7047

# Summary\_

Looking for a job as a Software Engineer. 8 years of programming experience with C/C++, Python and Java, specializing in system programming and backend/infrastructure. Proficient in Relational Database Management Systems, especially MySQL. Experienced with Big Data technology such as Hadoop and Hive. Good exposure to NoSQL databases such as MongoDB and HBase.

# Skills

Languages C/C++, Python, Java, SQL, Shell, HTML, R

**Database Systems** MySQL, SQLite, Oracle, MongoDB, HBase

**Operating Systems** Linux/Unix, Mac OSX

**Frameworks** Hadoop, Hive, Giraph, Pthreads, MPI, MapReduce, Django

Tools LaTeX, Emacs, Eclipse, Git, Vagrant, Puppet, Chef

# Education \_\_\_

### **University of Arizona**

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, GPA: 3.18

#### **University of St. Thomas**

M.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, GPA: 3.8

#### **Harbin Institute of Technology**

B.E. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Tucson, Arizona USA

Aug. 2014 - May. 2017

St. Paul. Minnesota USA

Aug. 2011 - May. 2014

Harbin, Heilongjiang China

Aug. 2014 - Aug. 2015, Aug. 2016 - Mar. 2017

Aug. 2004 - May. 2008

# **Experience**

#### **University of Arizona**

RESEARCH ASSISTANT WITH DR. RICHARD SNODGRASS ON ANTARES PROJECT

Tucson, Arizona USA

• Designed and implemented the Python API for astronomical alert data manipulation, using MySQL as DB backend.

- · Worked on various components of ANTARES system, including data injection, alert simulator and alert packet format specification.
- Managed the dedicated CentOS cluster; designed and built the autoconfiguration and bootstrap system using Puppet and Vagrant.
- · Analyzed and improved the performance of ANTARES data processing pipeline; researched data provenance.

## **University of Arizona**

Tucson, Arizona USA Spring 2016 & Fall 2016

INDEPENDENT STUDY WITH DR. BEICHUAN ZHANG ON NAMED DATA NETWORKING (NDN) PROJECT

• Researched consumer-driven congestion control mechanisms in NDN.

· Implemented TCP-like congestion control algorithms in NDN consumer (in C++), specifically, TCP RENO, CUBIC and VEGAS.

# **University of Arizona**

Tucson, Arizona USA Fall 2015 & Spring 2016

TEACHING ASSISTANT WITH DR. LESTER McCann on CS460: DATABASE SYSTEMS

- · Held office hours; graded programming and written assignments; prepared solutions for written assignments.
- Designed the final project "Database-driven Web Application" using Oracle, Tomcat and JSP; evaluated students' design and implementation.

## **University of St. Thomas**

St. Paul, Minnesota USA

STUDENT RESEARCHER WITH DR. BRAD RUBIN AND DR. JADIN JACKSON ON PROJECT: NEURAL MODELING IN HADOOP

Aug. 2013 - May. 2014

- Researched graph processing in Hadoop.
- Implemented the neural network with both MapReduce model and vertex-centric model (using Apache Giraph).

## **Danfoss Power Solutions** SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Plymouth, Minnesota USA

June. 2012 - May. 2013

- Migrated the legacy software to the new hardware platform with other team members and conducted unit testing.
- Built a backend tool (in Python) for indexing and querying large volume of messages produced by static code analyzer FlexeLint.

#### Platomix Technologies. (Start-up company)

Beijing, China

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2009 - July. 2009

- Being part of a team that built the initial prototype for Samsung's Remote Test Lab (RTL), I was responsible for the development on RTL device.
- Implemented the communication protocol (in C++) between RTL device (LiMo platform) and RTL proxy.
- Developed a daemon process (in C++) for RTL device to handles requests from proxy, in order for RTL client to remotely control the device.

SHUO YANG · RÉSUMÉ JULY 14, 2017